namaste Namaskar wanna come Selam
aleykum sri akaal and good morning to
the each one of us who's joined in for a
very special show here at wellness 360
at home
brought to you by ICICI Lombard well
today 21st June 2020 has its own touch
feel and most importantly it's got a
great vibe of mental health well-being
wellness pink thread and musical
thinking about now most of you already
know it but recited in a poetic style
that today is international yoga day at
the same time it is also world music day
and if these two are not enough please
also Father's Day so yes I want to wish
you all as we start the amazing special
show great hero
well s3t stay at home and wish you all
great music great yogic feel and of
course
Dualla dad is there happy Father's team
now today just about an hour back our
Honorable Prime Minister rose on screen
and said today across India
it's not gonna be international yoga day
but we will be celebrating yoga at home
and Yuga with family so we thought let's
bring this whole thing with family back
home to everyone who's watching us back
being at home this is one time that you
get to be at the best of who you are and
become the best version of who you are
so that's why we are here bringing you
the amazing field of yoga in two very
amazing way let's get ready cuz we have
an amazing amazing guest today and she's
here to help you become a better version
of would you bar so are we ready
if yes let's get ready remember it isn't
mad cuz it's going to be an amazing
amazing start to 21st June 2020 just a
quick reminder what does yoga really
mean Yoga means coming together to 90
unite in with yourself cuz it's time
that you have so many things around your
head but get back to yourself be with
you and become better so now it's time
that we bring in our very best sure at
wellness 360 at home
joining us is a celebrity host guest and
also someone who masters in fitness and
more well who is she
well she's the master Pilates trainer
you go instructor from the Yoga Nidra
Institute Pilates educationist
celebrating fitness trainer
nutritionist and a co-author of pure and
healthy a healthy Indian cookbook is
also a nutritionist in India to go water
of Kabul that's right she has a master
degree from the u.s. in nutrition and
addition and a fellowship in real scent
and sports medicine well she has moved
back to India about 12 years ago and
she's now working with famous
celebrities of Bollywood and many other
business tycoons
well she's equipped with amazing studio
in Bombay and she has everything that a
studio needs but with all that including
Pilates and yoga the only studio and
offers a combination of yoga and block
is together so ladies and gentlemen to
be delighted to welcome here at the
Wellness 360 at home brought to you by
ICICI Lombard is going to be Radhika
Carly with us right now
I love the car good morning good to see
you a fantastic feel looking at you it's
even more vibrant because you have the
vibes of spreading happiness but you
know international yoga day we are
delighted to have you and how you feel
this morning and how how does how does
be yoga
thank you missing first for the
fantastic introduction and it feels
great it feels great to be able to give
whatever knowledge that I have back to
the community and really look forward to
spreading a little bit of perhaps joy
perhaps happiness but very much like
what you said is Yoga is a
union of the mind the body the spirit so
we're really working on that aspect in
today's session and you know I'm excited
I already have my bat ready and I'm sure
everyone was watching us back home or
wherever you are be ready with the mat
cause it's gonna be something very
delightful and other guys can't wait so
over to you now let the Wellness 360 at
home begin or a very special day the
international yoga day with Radhika
thank you thank you missing and welcome
everyone and happy world yoga day so as
I mentioned yoga is the union of the
mind the body and the spirit so we are
trying to gonna try today in our session
to bring all three of these together I
understand that during this time many
people may be facing different emotions
different feelings this is a time like
no other I don't know about you but I've
never been through a pandemic so but I
have learned that my yoga practice has
truly helped me in dealing with a lot of
the emotions I'm not gonna say I'm stoic
the emotions do come and go but it's my
yoga practice that has kept me grounded
so I'm gonna start with a little story
20 years ago I was a nutritionist for a
big chain of gyms in the US and probably
about the umpteenth time that someone
came in for a consult and they said that
oh you're Indian can you teach me yoga
and I had to say no I'm sorry I don't
know anything about yoga and by like I
said the umpteenth time I finally
decided it's time that I learned this
age-old practice that everyone in the
West wants to take on and I should be
able to do then give that knowledge back
so sure enough I packed my bags and I
returned to India and I did an intensive
course in yoga at the Yoga Institute in
in Bombay here and I came to the
Institute thinking that okay it's gonna
build strength I'm gonna build muscles
and I'm gonna do these ass not that I'm
gonna get strong but the whole time I
was there we talked about the effects
that Yoga has on the mind and then
brought those in with the asanas so
today what we're really gonna do is
we're gonna talk about the mind is a
little bit and then we're gonna bring in
those yo-yo yoga asanas and figure out
how those yoga asanas are gonna help us
through certain difficulties or certain
emotions that we are feeling the two
things that stayed with me so I'm very
proud to say that that was 20 years ago
so I was a bright young sprightly 22
year old during that time and I'm 14 to
you today and I have never felt so
strong and so connected with my body and
I have to give a lot of that credit to
the movements that I do the two things
that stuck with me throughout the time
and through these 20 years is number one
yoga teaches you to stay in the present
to stay in the present and really focus
on the present forget about the past
don't worry about the future but really
stay in the present so today as we go
through some movement and some asanas I
really urge you all to stay in the
present there may be a child screaming
in the background ma ma ma ma tell them
it's Father's Day go do you live with
your data or you may be thinking what am
I gonna make for breakfast what am I
gonna make for lunch try to push that
away those thoughts will come and go but
try to stay in the present right the
second thing that to the yoga practice
taught me and that has really helped me
through this time is that every movement
has a breath pattern attached to it so I
will be giving you cues on the breath
pattern as we go into certain movements
but I really want you to stay focused on
that breathing not only helps calm us
down so we've heard so much about
pranayama and the power of braun I am
and how breathing can really help
bring us back in to a less anxious state
and a less frustrated straight state but
when you match the breathing with your
movements that brings a different type
of power and energy breathing can
facilitate movement so if you feel like
some of the movement is very difficult
focus on the breathing that I'm cueing
you through so that way you can maybe
feel a little bit of a difference in
your movement with the breathing pattern
right so without further ado we're gonna
talk a little bit about some of the
emotions that some of us might be going
through match them up with a yoga flow I
truly believe that movement is medicine
so we really need to be moving right in
order to really heal our bodies and of
course with the healing of the body
there should be a healing of the mind as
well the first emotion that I want to
talk about is anxiety anxiety comes with
a feeling of worry fear uncertainty
however with movement you are releasing
endorphins endorphins are your happy
hormones and that should then take you
out of the state of anxiety so we start
our first round of movement with what I
like to call warm-up so we're gonna come
to warm acts now I'm gonna start first
with Watson so triangle pose this is a
great way to get large muscles going
through really gonna feel your legs
working you're gonna get the spine
moving the spine is the center of your
body that really holds you up right I'm
sure a lot of you have been spending
time here over your devices so I'm gonna
try to open that spine up and see how
the feeling of energy of power comes
back to you in some of these simple
moves the feet are a little bit further
than shoulder width apart your toes are
pointing straight out in front we talked
about a triangle on the switch as well
so think this is gonna then think about
the triangle on your foot as well the
triangle on your foot is your heel your
big toe
and your pinky toe try to keep the
weight in that triangle on your foot
even that triangle is the base and it's
gonna ground you down the grounding down
is really gonna take you out of the
state that you're in we start first with
a nice simple lateral stretch there's
gonna be movement everyone remembered
mat your breath with the movement we're
burning the left arm up close to the ear
shoulder draws down and overlay your hip
bones are pointing straight out in front
there are headlights on your car you do
not want to turn them on the inhale
we're gonna inhale through the nose
we're gonna reach up and over while
keeping the hip bones pointing straight
out in front and on the exhale we return
all the way back up hand comes back down
to the side we come to the opposite
right arm reaches up I'm close to the
ear draw the shoulders are down in a way
we inhale we reach up and over feel a
big stretch now most often we want to
kind of see I want you to remember that
triangle up in the hood keeper we make
equal on both the triangles of your feet
shall we come up let's do that again
couple one more time we reach up and
over we inhale hip bones pointing
straight out in front about creating
length through both sides of the body a
lot of the times we want to focus on the
reaching and we forget about creating
length if you create length through both
sides to the waist that also take this
away from that feeling of sinking think
about reaching up there is a
metaphorical aspect to every movement
let's do that again we reach up and over
we inhale create that length grind those
hips down straight out in front I'm at
shall we come back up one more time arm
comes up check in again make sure that
the weight is equal on the triangle of
both your feet on all the way up one
more time this time I'm going to add in
one more cue inhale we reach up and over
this time I want everyone to think about
keeping the pelvis in the center of the
body so don't let the weight slide over
to the
no I say no we return back to the top
one last one reach up now don't lose
this reach up as you reach over keeping
reaching up keep reaching up as you
reach over check in with the feet annek
so we come all the way back up let's add
in a rotation here now another solid
movement that really helps to take us
out of that state of anxiety so think
about your upper body as a wet towel and
you want to wring the water out of the
towel we start put the arms up and level
with the shoulders again think of the
reach here the reach is reaching out to
the two sides of the room keep the ears
over the shoulders on the inhale we're
gonna rotate to the right side again
your hip bones remain pointing straight
out in front so as you rotate to the
right really focus on pressing my right
hip forward
don't let it travel back behind you
exhale we come back in to Center we go
to the opposite side we inhale now again
we're grounding the feet down but we're
reaching the crown of the head up to the
ceiling exhale back to Center in here we
wrote in a Suzanne a couple more times
to each side and exhale back to Center
add that deep breathing breathe in
breathe out so I'm taking my breath out
from my mouth because that is going to
help keep me a little bit more Center
through these feelings centering becomes
one of the most important aspects one
more time we inhale to rotate exhale
back in last time to the opposite side
making sure the weight is equal on both
your feet exhale we come back into
Center hands come down by your sides we
take it now out to our second flow of
movement little bit more advanced a
little bit more energy added to this
because remember this is warm-up we take
the feet out a little bit further than
hip width apart so your feet should be
almost three and a half to four feet
apart you should feel a nice stretch to
your inner thighs your toes are still
pointing out in front we're gonna go
into an extended angle and from an
extended angle we're gonna go into a
reverse warrior for those of you
practicing your
regularly you may understand these
asanas all these movements otherwise
listen to my cues we're gonna turn the
right foot so that your heel is in line
with the arch of the left foot
this movement now is going to further
warm you up further get you energized
remember focus on the breathing we bend
the front right knee as you bend the
knee try to get that side parallel to
the floor I'm gonna take my feet off a
little bit further so I can get a little
bit more than lowering I'm working on
grounding down again focus on the
triangle of the foot keep that weight
equal on the triangle we reach the arms
out at level with the shoulders again
focus on the reach hip bones are still
pointing straight out in front we lower
the front right hand all the way down if
you can all the way down to the floor
reaching the top hand up think about
that oppositional reach you're grounding
down you're reaching up if the hand
doesn't lower down all the way to the
floor the grounding down from here we
have exhales in this position on the
inhale we're going to reach the right
arm up lower the left hand down across
the back of the thigh and we go again we
exhale we reach up and over
think about that again you can reach up
and over over here if you have shoulder
issues you can get the arm straight up
to the ceiling hand goes down to the
floor if you can exhale we reach up
ground those feet down draw the
shoulders down in the way here we go
again we exhale exhale option two inhale
heart up see how the breathing is gonna
facilitate your movement exhale and
inhale one last one remember everyone
this is warming up you should really
feel warmed up we reach grab on those
legs down use that front right leg
really pressing into that foot
I'm return to that starting position leg
straightens up we turn the feet
obviously you want to equal yourself up
we're gonna go to the other side turn
the foot heel in line with the arch lift
the arms up check in headlights of the
hips
pointing straight out in front reach
really reached I want you to think about
that oppositional force heart up chin up
arms reaching Bend the fun to me take
the game is straight out in front try to
lower those hips down as much as you can
I'm from here first our extended angle
bring the hand down to the floor if you
can take the gaze up to the ceiling it's
not there remember hand to the shin and
we reach up we inhale and here we go
again we can do forearm to thigh reach
up and over a little bit of an extra
stretch jump master breath make it a
strong breath everyone we exhale and we
inhale grandpa's feet down reach for
more and and three your breathing should
be loud inaudible and up focus on
lowering those hips down to really
ground yourself up one last one with
that breath we exhale and we inhale to
reach up straighten the arms up
straighten the feet up turn the feet so
they're in and walk the feet back in
warm up so I hope you guys are all
warmed up with that the two takeaways
here number one the triangle in the foot
remember that triangle keep it grounded
down as we go into some more standing
poses think of that triangle being at
the ground and being down through this
flow you should have felt number one
energy through the entire body number
two you should have felt movement in the
spine your spine is literally the
backbone of your body so think about
that movement we work a lot on movement
through the mid-back which is really
important because as we go through our
day we're starting to become more and
more like this so we're really gonna
work on opening up our next flow of
rounds now so round two
going to work on frustration many of you
may have been feeling frustration panic
goes along with anxiety because of the
unknown because of the uncertainty
frustration also happens and during this
time of frustration the best thing to do
is stand up during times of frustration
we end up being like this a lot every
think it's very tight everything gets
very stiff the standing asanas that we
are now going to take you into are the
warrior series there is no one better
than the warrior for us to understand
how to get out of times of frustration
when we think of a warrior we think of
focus we think of mental strength and
these series of asanas now we're gonna
do three together are really gonna help
us overcome these feelings of
frustration and maybe even anxiety that
comes along with this so our next round
of movements is stand up so here we go
back to our mats now in outward warrior
series which is veerabhadra's and your
feet are going to be a little bit
further apart so I rub my feet almost
three and a half to four feet apart they
should be far enough apart so that you
can feel a nice stretch to the inner
thigh we're gonna take it back to that
same position that we were just in for
extended angle pose we're gonna turn the
right foot heel is in line with the arch
of the left foot I'm going to separate
my feet out a little bit more I turn my
upper body up over my right knee hips
are still pointing straight out in front
I'm doing a little bit of an
oppositional force here thumbs come up
to my chest palms together I'm gonna
bend into the front of me I'm trying to
get my front thigh to become parallel to
the floor here I take a deep inhale
reach the arms up overhead into my
warrior one once again focus on that
grounding of your feet the triangle of
your friction really
yourself hard up remember stand up tall
through this series from here nominee
take it into our warrior two arms extend
and out again think about that in reach
don't move the legs hold here
think about the mental strength and
focus that is required to be a warrior
take the gaze over the front hand reach
legs ground down arms reach up so I'm
here not will you take it into a warrior
three which is a balancing pose you may
want to watch me and then follow along
we're going to lift up off the back
right leg the arms are gonna come up
framing the face we noticed we reached
our I'm gonna try to bring the body into
a nice tea if you're having a hard time
with the balance here lower the foot
down and just keep the toes down
otherwise lift the leg up by focusing on
one point on the floor you're gonna hold
breathe three two one
lower the foot back down to the original
position take it back to your warrior
two take that reach once again warrior
one thumbs to the chest turn the upper
body lift the arms up with in here
warrior two we exit and warrior when we
inhale lift up to three whole take the
gaze down draw the shoulders away from
the ears focus on that triangle
understanding but again reach arms in
opposition to the legs lower back down
one more time everyone we reach warrior
one thumbs to chest
we inhale heart of China think the
backgrounder warrior two we reach arms
out in opposition and warrior three on a
strong inhale arms up lift up whole
balance requires focus requires strength
and requires grounding down slowly come
back down and obviously we do one side
we go to the other take the feet out
match the breath
turn the foot heel in line with the
arches arms up lean into it turn the
upper body thumbs to the chest
we inhale lift the arms up ground that
leg down now this one I want you to
really think about challenging yourself
really work on that mental strength to
bring the legs down and hold the
position here we hold reach the arms up
upper body turns to face forward arms go
out in opposition and now turning the
upper body again arms up level with the
ears and then the strong in here we push
off the front foot onto the front foot
hold the balance reach the arms out
remember focus on that one point try to
get the hip bones to be pointing
straight down to the floor and we return
back to the warrior two turn to warrior
one we inhale arms up shoulders down
ground those legs down exhale warrior
two chest open shoulders relaxed inhale
arms up press off warrior three reach
reach an opposition focus strength and
balance back down last two we reach turn
the upper body inhale exhale
inhale reach long and strong opposition
ground the foot down last one reach
inhale arms up try to get those hip
bones to be pointing straight out in
front shoulders down and away from the
ears worrier to breathe out I'm over
year three back to the balance we're
gonna hold the balance for a count of
three now here hold three two one lower
back down turn the feasts of their
parallel lower the hands back down by
your sides
you should have felt some serious work
to the upper body some serious work to
the legs and there is our stand up
series so now the entire body is going
in and we have really added the upper
body as well if you are in any sort of a
mental state that is away from being
happy or being at peace the first place
that that is mimicked is in your upper
body our upper body lies closest to our
brain and therefore emotions are
mirrored in our upper body you're
feeling sad you're feeling stressed or
frustrated so it is a matter of really
working the upper body in order to get
your mental state also in a better place
there are many asanas in yoga that work
on releasing the upper body and moving
the upper body to get you in a better
place so our next now round of series
we're going to look into the aspect of
depression
now I'm not a clinical psychologist I'm
not a therapist although I end up being
one sometimes in my sessions but with
depression
there are many a times and a hormonal
imbalance that occurs with depression
there are several asanas that not only
as I mentioned open up through the open
you up through the upper body but also
simulant stimulates your pituitary gland
your pituitary gland is the central
control system for all the other glands
in your body that release hormones so we
are going to now go into some asanas
that work on stimulating this pituitary
gland and take you out of hormonal
balances which mode may potentially also
be leading to a state of depression
remember work on mal chin up
our next set our next round we are
calling chill out so think about lifting
that chin up the chin up automatically
relates to a lifting of the upper body
we're gonna start now lying down on your
back so we're gonna go back to our
mouths and we're gonna start with bridge
tones bridge Falls which is also known
as say to London is a fantastic way to
strengthen you up through the backs of
your leg but it's also a great way to
open you up through the front and
there's a little bit of simulation
simulation of your pituitary gland that
happens here we lie down on our back our
hands are down by your sides hips knees
and ankles are in line arms are reaching
down by the sides on a strand inhale we
want to lift the hips up so we're gonna
start with a little modification here
bring the weight onto the back of the
shoulders the chin is up the gaze is up
to the ceiling again think about that
triangle in your foot ground the weight
equally between a big toe little toe and
heel now from here across the hand
underneath try to lift those hips up a
little bit more squeezing through the
backs of the legs
I'll only exhale we're gonna release the
hands I'm gonna down through the spine
one vertebrae at a time while keeping
your collar bones why and remember this
is chin up I'll again get you the snout
a bit more of a variation making it a
little
more challenging draw your heels closer
to your bucket kneecaps are pointing up
to the ceiling
remember chin up knees up ground the
feet down on a strong inhale we bridge
the hips up reach the knees away from
you keep that chin up
keep your collar bones wide keep the
weight pressing on the backs of the
shoulders you're trying to become a
straight line from your knees to your
shoulders
try not to hyperextend the back you
don't want to dump into the lower back
here and again on a strong exhale we
roll down through the side let's do that
three more time chin up
inhale press the hips up reach your
heels to your shoulders as you reach
your kneecaps away from you exhale we
roll back down through the spine look
nowhere but up two more we inhale we
bridge up keep the weight e full under
feet try to keep those hips level exhale
roll down as you roll down keep reaching
your tailbone away from you to stretch
the spine out one last one we inhale we
bridge up remember the weight is on the
back of your shoulders not on your head
you should be able to lift your head up
to give me that chin up and exhale we
roll down slowly with control now they
take it into one more awesome much in
the Sun which is fish pose really very
powerful to get that pituitary gland
going get those hormones in balance and
gets that mental states in a really
great place we stretch the legs out now
here we're gonna do a little bit of a
modification first we're going to the
first to the philosophy from here the
hands are down by the sides all I'm
going to think about is chin up we're
gonna lift the chin up with the chin up
think that someone has buddy hook on
your heart and then lifting your heart
up towards
so there's gonna be a small little
bridge that's gonna happen slow movement
to beginning we inhale exhale slowly
roll down through the upper back to
return to that flat position let's try
that two more times inhale chin up heart
lifts up to the ceiling think about
pressing down firmly through the forearm
exhale slowly back down one more time
legs are zipped together draw your toes
towards your face
we inhale heart up chin up feel slowly
back down now taking it into the full
much of nothing we're gonna bend the
knees to begin with and we're gonna lift
the hips up clasp the hands underneath
you and from here now you're going to
bring the I'm trying to lift the heart
up now from here if possible stretch one
leg up stretch the other leg out you are
a bridge the top of your top of the head
feel we slowly roll down a little bit
more challenging much better one more
time this time with the legs straight
huh these are fast together bring the
top of your head down now we track those
shoulder blades three three two one
slowly roll back down chin to chest
I believe so shoulders release those arm
and slowly come up chin up we take it
into two more movements for chin up now
we're going to lie down on our summer
when we lie down on our summer I want
you to focus on engaging through your
Center another way to ground you down
chin up on are some of them lying down
on your stomach we're gonna take it into
two oznas here we have google Dawson and
we have Shire Boston - fantastic
movements to work on lifting up and as
well as work on that upper body strength
a little bit we start first with woojong
have the level with the shoulders legs
are reaching me huh I want everyone to
think about as they inhale and lift the
heart up draw the shoulders down press
down the toes into your mat so it's
really important if those toes press
down so that you stay engaged to the
backs of your legs and there isn't a
whole bunch of dumping that happens into
the lower back exhale we slowly lower
back down
although huijeong Dawson is working on
flexibility of the spine inhale we lift
we want to make sure that we are also
working on keeping the lower back safe
exhale slowly lower back down but
pressing down and that reaching of the
toes really helps to support the lower
back
in chin up heart up shoulders down
exhale slowly back down one more time
everyone we inhale lift the heart draw
the shoulders away neck launch Anna I'm
exhale slowly down we're going to take
it now into all of the shuttle bus and I
wish all of us in is a great way to
strengthen the backs of the legs the
chin is up the odds are down by your
sides
angle your chin down onto the mat chin
up the top of your mat about now you
have a small of your back you do not
want to spill that coffee as you go into
this either shuttle bus and if the palm
facing up or causing your shoulders to
run forward you can press the palms down
into the mat that also works very well
chin down onto the mat this time on a
strong engagement through the back of
the leg chin up everyone don't tuck that
chin exhale we slowly lower back down to
the opposite side as
abdominals engage by drawing the belly
button into the spine let's do that
three more times to each side chin stays
grounded chin stays up we inhale to lift
exhale to lower one more time inhale we
reach and lift exhale lower and last
time to each side try to keep the leg
long keep the shoulders away from the
ears but keep the chin up one last one
we inhale and exhale to slowly lower
here we go let's challenge ourselves
underneath our joined under actually
exhale we low and bring the hands up
relax the right cheek down onto the mat
take two deep breaths
switch relax your left chief on the mat
and take two deep breaths and now
hopefully everyone is in a nice chin-up
situation we've done warm-up we've done
stand-up we've done chin up and now it's
time to perk up with perk up we are
going to work on combatting loneliness
we are social beings as humans and
during this lockdown period you might be
feeling moments of loneliness through
this next series of exercise which I
have termed perk up perk up is going to
focus on you becoming self-sufficient
becoming strong from the center and is
going to work a little bit on your self
development it is through self
development that we become at peace with
ourselves we become comfortable being
alone the lonely list should hopefully
not last too long as I keep telling
myself this too will pass but in the
meantime here are a few of us that are
going to really focus on self
development and get you self independent
and ok with being on your own for
hopefully not too much longer we're
gonna take it back to our max again and
we're gonna come on to all fours in the
old horse position the knees are
underneath the hips and the hands from
underneath the shoulders once again I
want you to imagine that your hot cup of
coffee your hot tea yes Yogi's drink
coffee and tea as well we're not all
just drinking water so that's sitting at
the small of your back you do not want
to spill your coffee which means your
hipbones are now pressing down to the
floor in this position you are fighting
gravity so core strength is of utmost
important here is a fantastic place to
develop core strength we start just real
nice and easy with an opposite arm leg
reach working into an officer which is
called bird dog
we reach
done and right leg think of the other
word which not what we say in yoga is
when something lifts something else has
to ground down so the grounding down has
to be at the opposite hand than the knee
really press down into your mat with the
opposite arm and leg to keep your cup of
whatever favorite beverage you have nice
and steady at the small of your back
we inhale to lift and we exhale to lower
back to the starting position let's
believe the opposite side inhale we
reach reach
think about that reach think about that
grounding down of the opposite I think
about that metaphor of grounding down
exhale we lower back down let's go to
the opposite side again inhale we reach
think about the length through the neck
keep your ears over your shoulders so
look straight down in front of your hand
that's grounded down exhale we lower one
more time inhale we reach exhale we
lower back down we're gonna add a little
bit of movements out here we're gonna
add a flexion and extension this is
after all her thump so the drop is gonna
come with a little bit of movement hands
underneath the shoulders legs are not
distant steady and firmly pressed down
you can't blame the tops of your toes
down if you want a little bit more
civility that's fine we reach left arm
and right leg from here draw the elbow
to the knee we exhale inhale we reach
and let me lift the heart up getting you
into that little perk up remember ground
down through the opposite side exhale
elbow to knee
tuck the tailbone underneath around the
background inhale lift the heart reach
the leg back behind you two more time we
exhale and we inhale try to keep the
knee over the hip the shoulder over the
wrist of the grounded arm and knee
thanks Hale and inhale and the exhale to
lower back down let's go to the opposite
side remember work from your Center draw
that belly button in we inhale we reach
keep your beverage steady exhale drop
all go to me tuck the tailbone tuck the
chin to the chest
I'll spin here we reach lift the heart
up reach the leg straight back up try
not to lift the leg back too far you do
not want to be arching the lower back
let's inhale heart up I'm acting I
inhale last you everyone stay with me
exhale inhale draw that belly button in
exhale and we lower back down once again
adding on a little bit of an aspect of
upper body strengthening over here and
also opening you up through your upper
body as I mentioned the emotional state
is all mirrored in your upper body so
really think about opening up through
the front of your body to help you
overcome some of these states we're
taking it into the last and final round
now everyone so a few more minutes over
here our last and final round is heart
up one of the most important muscles in
your body is your heart it doesn't
matter how big your biceps are how
strong your legs are if your heart is
not strong there's no way you're going
to go during this time we are feeling
immense amounts of stress because of the
uncertainty because of mounting
pressures from work from home children
homeschooling
online all of this adds to someone's
stress it's very easy to say don't
stress but one of the easiest ways
through yoga to combat the stress is
simply moving from one asana to the next
so adding in a vinyasa below if you
please and that flow that's the heart
rate to come up you are exercising your
heart and therein we call this sequence
heart shot
so to any width we're going to do a
small little vinyasa flow here the flow
is gonna start in folic acid which is
our plank post and we're gonna take it
from there into a few again here is a
great place to work on core strength so
we go back to that whole idea of really
working on self-defense
Lippman and yoga is one the fantastic
wide one running most I would say
effective ways to really work on
self-development here we go hearts up
our last fifth and final rounds we're
going to come to our maps in our plank
position our hands are underneath our
shoulders we stretch our legs out become
a long strong straight line from the top
of your head to your heels try to keep
your heels underneath your toes squeeze
through the backs of your legs from here
we're gonna take it into our downward
facing dog press the heels down to the
ceiling
draw the ribcage back towards your heels
and now from here back to our plank
position from the plank position we're
gonna lift off of one hand come to your
side clamp as you come to your side
plank try to rotate on your feet press
the bottom hip forwards and we exhale
come back to the plank in here we come
to the side plank to the opposite side
we see Emma slopes on up and turn the
head exhale back to your side plank and
now from here we're going to take it
into our lizard pose inhale we're gonna
draw that right foot all the way up as
high as you possibly can if your foot
can't come all the way up to the
Highness I as a cat reach the extended
hip forward
so the extended leg hip goes forward and
we draw the leg back as you exhale
inhale opposite hand opposite foot comes
up to the hand press the hips forward
remember this is hike ups and I'll lift
the heart up take the gaze straight out
in front try to keep the weight equal on
the hands and we exhale take the foot
back inhale back to our downward facing
dog press the heels down reach your sit
bones those are the bony joints in your
butt up to the ceiling and exhale back
to your plank flow holes
inhale to the side plank lift the hand
up exhale back to your plank inhale to
the opposite side
we want to get that heart rate going up
just a little bit exhale back to the
plank inhale walk the right foot up
press the hips forward heart up here
everyone exhales would come back put up
as much as possible
and inhale foot up heart exhale back to
the plan
inhale downward facing dog one more time
everyone with me exhale plank inhale
side plank press on others and we're
grounding down through the hammer you
think about pressing the floor away
exhale back to your plank inhale side
plank exhale back to the plank inhale
walk that foot up heart up exhale back
inhale walk the foot up on the opposite
side heart up exhale back now slowly
lower the knees down sit it back down
onto your heels lower your chest down
onto your thighs when you take it into
balancing standing here Child's Pose
here move the forehead down onto the
mount ground yourself down and take four
deep breaths deep inhale try to breathe
into the spaces in your back exhale two
more times deep inhale into the spaces
in your back
I'm exhale on the last breath really
think about pressing your chest down
heavy onto your thighs to allow for a
little bit more space in your back to
let the breath go into your back that
might have become a little tight over
these past several weeks of lockdown
slowly come up and we're done with our
warmup
stand up chin up perk up and heart I
hope you enjoyed the sequences and I
hand it back over to Mithun now for some
questions thank you
and certainly already on the ground so
that was beautiful that was indeed
beautiful the best part is how you
explained every Asuna and what
advantages it has from heart to heart as
most strongest part of it so anything
you do I work from home stress and many
of the stress how to means it's writing
exactly what wellness and you know if
she at home means giving everything and
thank you so much it was beautiful we
love here every especially and I think
we couldn't get better than what you
just taught us right now so yes my
husband is beautiful I receive many
questions that's coming in so radical if
you ready we can do all the questions ok
let's get the questions really
I see interesting ones the first
question that's coming in is a very
straightforward question I think
everyone would love to know I'm sure
you've already explained this but
neither is asking what are the
boundaries of yoga every day I'm gonna
say there are three key advantages
needed number one is the mind-body
connection that you get through yoga
there are very few other forms of
exercise the other form of exercise that
I practice is Pilates Pilates is the
other form so when I join my my
yoga practice of my Pilates practice
those really helped me so the mind-body
connection number one number two the
mobility and the flexibility that you
gain from yoga is really second to none
again maybe Pilates comes close but but
the flexibility is really really amazing
which again no other form of movement
can do and I think the third one which I
haven't gone over but I think there's a
lot of information out there is the
power of pranayama
so Ron I am which is specific to yoga is
super super powerful and especially
during a time like this really because I
do so as I mentioned at the beginning
Yoga is union of the mind the body and
the spirit
so that union of all three really helps
you and as far as mental well-being is
concerned you get very centered also
staying in the present Yoga is another
form of movement you can't be thinking
about what you're gonna make for lunch
who you're gonna meet for dinner where
you're going to go what are your kids
going you have to stay focused on the
movement so there is there's a lot of
centering and there's a lot of focus
that comes which really helps as far as
mental well-being is concerned so let's
go to the next question now the next
question is coming from someone called
is Shawn
Sharma he's asked me any diet advice
which you would want to give to yoga so
that was one of the biggest things when
I joined the yogi inner Institute is
that we so we would always joke that
every other day was Doody and so the
joke between our between my batch was
that do the same so that's why I was
like Doody but actually it was it was
sattvic yeah there was no garlic if
there's no onions now that's a little
difficult I'm not I'm not gonna say you
have gone to my back to my sausage
routes but what you have to understand
as far as nutrition is concerned is you
need to stick to seasonal fresh and
indigenous so what is it that we eat in
this belt what is it that is in season
here and also remember our need for
calories is very small very small so
Shawn to reach out to us for for
nutrition we do we do personalized
nutrition as well so but your needs are
actually very small and especially less
now unless you're doing try to portray
every day your your needs for calories
are really not that big so I think that
also as Thank You shant the question we
moved forward was another question was
normal question everybody's asking is
should we do it every day should we do
it alternate days or there is any
particular days you know bring that one
should do yoga so what's your take on
that Radhika
you should practice yoga he in and day
out and now so I'm gonna say that again
you're gonna practice yoga day in and
day out because the essence of yoga is
union of mind body and spirit and the
essence of your guys staying in the
present now as far as asanas are
concerned I know that's where the
question is directed to as far as asanas
are concerned do it every day
just make sure you're varying it up so
if one day you're gonna focus on asanas
that are more focused towards your lower
body the next day focus on upper bodies
you're not bombarding the same muscles
over and over again and just remember
spinal mobility very important which
yoga has do that every day
that should keep it up every day you
will be doing yoga practice when you
feel best there is not a magical yoga
hour you should exercise when you feel
best because if you're gonna force
yourself to do it you're not gonna be
there completely mentally or even
physically so exercise when you feel
best just important that you move every
day for the best ten of you go for you
let me ask the question it is anytime
between 5:30 to 6:30 a.m. I my day
starts very early I'm up at 5:00 okay
questions this was an interesting
question that's coming in today's
international yoga day it is also world
music day what's the connection that you
find in between these two big major
events of life there is a huge
connection within I think both have very
powerful therapeutic aspects you so I
during this lockdown period everyone
talked about picking up a new skill and
I wasn't a new skill but I went back to
playing my sitar and there is a
meditative aspect to both yoga as well
as music so and it's not only about
listening to music I think listening to
music is very important but I think
playing music so it's never too late to
learn I'm 42 and I've picked it up again
after 25 years that's when I last played
my safar so there is a meditative aspect
and so I think there is a very big
connect between the two and also in the
West the West has done a fantastic job
of creating a whole genre of music for
yoga so and they have seen that there
with that percussive beat or with that
with that the the rhythm you can
actually get someone's body to flow a
lot better so that's if you've got the
rhythm in you which is doing what the
slowest and like
said you know there's a big connection
like even when you breathe in as well is
it musical then that goes in a new
business vessel there's a big connection
and anything what happens is having a
good some music day Yoga is meant to be
together and that's how it works
together in one hand last question or
take I have like so many questions a
little confusing but let me choose the
best one this is a question that's
coming or mostly women oriented and the
question is then please suggest yoga
because because PCOS yes if you're asked
it's a or D so the ones that we did in
the middle where I did chin up so chin
up all four of those asanas so we did
say to bond us and bridges bridge pose
we did much embarrassin which is fish
pose we did bridge on malson and we did
shallow basin all of those have an
effect on the pituitary gland the
pituitary gland is your central control
system for all other releases of
hormones so it controls the other glands
that release hormones so those are
really good but along with that the
major connect with PCOS is your
lifestyle so you again stay in the stay
in the present go to bed early wake up
early have a clean nutrition plan but
yoga these these chinna pastas can
really really help as well upper body
does wonders with your workout and
asanas concentrate they are interesting
most of your problems will be resolved
in no time and so thank you so much
rather cut is one last question if you
had to describe wellness 368 home which
is a platform that I see a yellow bar is
bringing from the whole log downtime
giving it all to different people in
terms of nutritionist latte fitness yoga
if you are described wellness risky at
home in one
what would that be all round it all
grounded
well that was radical giving us more
than inside towards how you can be LD
and be smiling all about Swan today
throughout your life if you get into
your if you haven't started today is
they take can promise yourself that you
will start yoga and under covers you're
helping us to get into yoga on his face
especially the international you got it
along with world music de Malaga thank
you so much on behalf the entire team of
ICICI Lombard I wanna thank you for
joining us this morning and it was
fantastic having you so thank you so
much again thank you so much within
thank you I CSU Lombard and happy yoga
day everyone stay well stay safe stay
home and stay strong
that's right straight strong and stay
completely well that's exactly what you
want you want to do so yes thank you so
much everyone who lovely no jokes this
morning or international you got in as
well as the world mobility it was lovely
having you all remember you start now
and start to get better cuz that's
exactly what they want you do with the
means of wellness 316 at home I see I
see yellow bar well we're your color
which is about I see a yellow bar and I
want you all to take the color of the
bride and go out there and become the
best version of you you are thank you so
much for joining us this is wellness it
gives you any feedback session go to our
Facebook page
wellness 360 at home and share your
thoughts said thank you again for
joining us have a great day enjoy your
day and make it best memories happy
international
you